KADONNA KNAPE

Austin, Tx 78745 | 512-694-1730 | kadonna.knape@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/kadonna-knape/ | Github: https://github.com/kknape | Portfolio: https://kknape.github.io/kadonna_portfolio/

SUMMARY

Software Project & Product Manager with experience taking digital products and business solutions from ideation to implementation. Effective at combining creativity and problem solving to realize any product vision or business goal. Passionate for life-long learning and empowering others to be successful no matter the obstacle, challenge or learning curve. A leader and collaborator with a proven record of success creating learning products, training solutions and meaningful digital experiences.

SKILLS AND TOOLS

Project Management: PMP, Agile, waterfall, iterative methodologies, MS Project, MS Office, G-suite **Instructional Systems**: Needs analysis, requirements gathering, implementation, training and enablement **Development & Technical**: Working knowledge of JavaScript, CSS, Bootstrap, jQuery, Node.js, Express, SQL, Firebase, Mongoose, MongoDB, React, Axios, GitHub, Jira/Atlassian, Salesforce

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Sourcing Specialist, Software & Technology Pearson K12 Learning

2019 – present Austin, TX

Support market analysis, vendor selection and procurement of development services across product development, platform and publishing technologies with direct impact on up to \$30 million in plant spending. Provide vendor identification, bidding to support budget planning, competitive bidding, bid analysis, assignment recommendation, contract pre-work, PO creation, and final project reconciliation.

Key Accomplishments in 2020:

Coordinate execution of dozens of new technology contracts and licenses to facilitate the new company in its complete and final separation from a larger global company.

Secured savings of almost half million dollars for digital and technology services and software through competitive bidding and pricing negotiations.

Customer Experience Project Manager Macmillan Learning

2017 - 2019

Austin, Tx

Provided project management and business process support for the Customer Experience (CX) team. Planned and managed the CX roadmap, in collaboration with stakeholders, that supported call center effectiveness. The CX roadmap included initiatives to enhance and extend our primary tool, Salesforce, to enable a successful customer feedback loop and improve our internal teams ability to empower and support our customers.

Key Accomplishments:

Led successful initiative to launch five new customer support sites that provide our diverse customer population a way to easily find answers to their questions and/or contact our support team, including back-end systems that capture meaningful data that informs our call center training program and support tools development roadmap.

Senior Producer Enspire Learning

2015 - 2017

Austin, Tx

Partnered with clients to understand their business needs, and then collaborated to implement effective instructional solutions for instructor-led, computer-based, and virtual training using proven instructional design models and methodologies.

Key Accomplishments:

- Led team of designers and developers in the creation of an award winning and commercially successful, 19 module multimedia, online continuing education course for nursing.
- Successfully led teams in the design and execution of media rich, experiential adult learning digital media projects, and supported the development of dozens of client solution proposals

Studio Production Manager

2013 - 2015

Toolwire

Pleasanton, CA

Oversaw the design and production teams in the development of experiential, video and game-based, online learning products.

Key Accomplishments:

Led team of designers and developers to create of four media rich online courses that incorporated real-world scenarios, 3-d environments, game mechanics and video to create immersive learning experiences for first year college students.

MultiMedia Production Manager

2012 - 2013

Istation Dallas, TX

Managed team of designers, animators, graphic artists and programmers to create online educational solutions for Pre-K - Fifth grade learners.

Key Accomplishments:

Improved efficiency and increased output of animation team by adopting scrum practices.

Product Manager Sunburst Digital

2011 - 2012

Austin, TX

Managed a small product development team at a fast-paced start-up. Leveraged new partner resources operating from Mexico City to create media rich educational websites and mobile apps.

Key Accomplishments:

- Successfully executed three month project to localize hundreds of media rich learning assets.
- Successfully executed six week project to convert over one hundred media rich flash assets to HTML5.

Data Portal Specialist

2010 - 2011

Texas Education Agency, Student Assessment Division

Austin, TX

Planned, implemented and supported quality assurance program for assessment reporting and data analysis.

Key Accomplishments:

Created and implemented data quality assurance processes for the Texas Assessment Teacher and Student Data Portal. Ensured that state and school administration requirements were met.

Sr. Project Manager

2004 - 2010

Houghton Mifflin Harcourt

Austin, TX

Served in several key areas as the company evolved -- Business Support Manager and Sr Project Manager for digital products, assessment and platforms.

Key Accomplishments:

- Planned and executed development of 50 digital, interactive books on time and under budget.
- Implemented processes to reduce overall digital course media production costs by 36%.

Product & Content Development Project Manager Ignite Learning

2000 - 2004

Austin, TX

Managed product development life cycle of the initial product offerings of Ignite Learning.

Key Accomplishments:

Implemented processes and coordinated design and development teams (local & offshore) to produce a full, digital curriculum of over 1000 distinct learning assets designed to meet education standards as well as the needs of diverse learners.

EDUCATION

University of Texas, Center for Professional Education, Coding Bootcamp

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

University of North Carolina, Bachelor of Fine Arts

Winston-Salem, NC